

# CONTACT



+91 97899 51528



dineshdhamodhiran@gmail.com

# **DINESH D**

# Packaging Graphic Designer

Dinesh, I undergo with following segment of my professional and personnel carrier. Challenging and rewarding position within the private sector where prior experience, personal ability, and a commitment to professionalism would be of value. Position should allow for continual personal and professional growth commensurate with achievements.

# **EDUCATION**

# Diploma in Printing Technology Institute of Printing Technology

IPT, Chennai, had got the degree of DPT with distinction.

2009-2012 / 82%

# School Graduation - S.S.L.C Govt. Higher Sec. School

At Mittur my hometown, had completed my schoolings with an average percentage.

2008-2009 / 69%

# FIELD INTEREST

Creative Designs
Photography
Cinematography
Animation

### EXTRA CURRICULUM

NSS
Kho-Kho, Volleyball
Mime
Tamil poets

# **INPLANT TRAINING**

TNQ Books and Journals, Chennai. One month - April 2012.

**Dhinagaran prints and Paper, Chennai.** One month – July 2012.

# **JOB EXPERIENCE**

# Olympus Premedia Pvt. Ltd.

Trainee Paginator September 2012 - March 2013 Chennai

# Scientific Publishing Services Pvt. Ltd.

Paginator March 2013 – June 2015 Chennai

#### Schawk India Pvt. Ltd.

Pre-Media Executive July 2015 - June 2018 Chennai

# Diadeis Packaging, SGSco

Senior Artwok Operator July 2018 – Aug 2020 Mauritius

### Schawk India Pvt. Ltd.

Senior Pre-press Artist Aug 2020 - Dec 2021 Chennai

### GlobalBees Brands Pvt. Ltd

Assistant Manager Dec 2021 - Present Bengaluru

# SKILL SET STATISTICS

# **SOFTWARE**

Illustrator, InDesign

**ESKO** 

Photoshop

MS Office

# **PERSONNEL ABILITY**

Organization

Communication

Team Synergy

Supportive Balance

Integrity

# **JOB PARTITION**

#### **Mechanical Artwork Build**

Converting the design files which are received from creative team into pre-print submission file as per client requirements with adherence of printing abilities and minimum targets.

### Reprographic Artwork

Making approved artworks from client end into print ready files with meeting the printer's requirements with high end quality level and accepting no limits.

### **DIS - Digital Imaging Solutions**

Complete shopping of photos, major criteria of photoshop to make the images into digital world which includes Hair Masking, Color Correction, Color Management, Rendering, Packshot, Color Separation, Illustration (line drawing).

### **Quality Control**

In scope of maintaining good quality and in demand of situation, had transferred as quality controller and retaining the quality of customer result with meeting all their brand set points internally.

#### **Client Service**

Same as QC, had undergone client servicing representative also, not only as mediator, but also to be awake always to get a perfect brief and satisfy client in all situations even in high pressure.

### **Preflight Analyst**

Forecasting the received job's from client which is perfect to start or do we have any inconvenience with the brief. Conflict's which impact the artwork will be highlighted immediately to recover clean start.

### **Artwork Coordinating**

Coordinator for packaging handles brand standards, guidelines and project reports. Creating new brands and its branding spec for all packaging stuffs.

# **TECHNICAL ACTIVITIES**

#### **Braille Creation**

Unreadable end users who are blind, especially for pharmaceutical products.

#### **Skeleton Creation**

Creating draft files with master die's and codes (FPO) for Non-Latin artworks which will be used as template for artwork creation

#### **Distortion**

Manual distortion for shrink sleeve packaging and stepped lid packaging for flexography.

## **Stepping**

Creating stepped output file using one-up PDF's for labels and conical packaging using Plato and Packedge.

#### 3D Creation

Creating 3D PDF's for conical labels (undistorted) in Photoshop and PDF's for regular label and boxes using Studio.

#### **Guideline Creation**

Creating master brand guidelines for the account with supplied client documents, approved regulatory procedures and approved artworks.

# **DESIGN-PREPRESS-PRINT**

ADOBE ESKO MS Office
Illustrator Artpro Word

InDesign Plato PowerPoint

Photoshop Pilot Excel

Acrobat Studio

3D

**Automation Engine** 

#### **PACKAGING**

Booklet, Pamlet, Brochure & Catalogue Carton
Corrugation – Outer Carton Tube

Conical Labels
Shrink Sleeve
Pouch & Sachet
Overwraps

# **ROLES & RESPONSIBILITY**

- Creates in accordance with approved artwork brief.
- Adheres to artwork production standards and Standard Operating Procedures
- Applying screen values, dot shape and angles for rotogravure and flexible packaging
- Proofing final outputs using printer profiles to calibrate right colors are achieved, matching vignettes and screen values to be successfully matching printers density
- Color matching between PMS and Process color and also EG colors at the time of reducing cylinder
- Working on Text and graphics to ensure its readability delivers standard human readable files
- Achieving font size, line thickness, text thickness for small packaging components like labels and sachets
- Ensures that artwork briefs and technical specifications are appropriate and complete before implementing the artwork
- Accountable for accuracy and completeness of own work before passing for artwork proofreading (QC) and review.
- Maintains data accuracy in the artwork production and storage processes
- Adheres to priorities and timelines for new and changed pack implementations, ensuring that any slippage or issues are escalated to appropriate levels of management and customers are fully informed of progress
- Ensures that accurate and complete artwork is dispatched to the correct printers / component suppliers
- Monitors and records own performance measures and participates in review of performance with the team and management, using operational excellence / lean sigma tools to improve KPIs and use of resources.
- Ensures that any quality compliance issues are promptly reported and investigated, and corrective actions are taken
- Able to work under demanding time pressures and constraints, and maintain an excellent standard of work
- Able to understand and manage complexity both from a technical and a people / cultural perspective
- Able to communicate effectively through a range of media, to various levels in the organization
- Training others in the use of artwork production system
- Maintains a safe and healthy work environment
- Volume and value of sales as determined by client served
- Adherence to regulatory and quality compliance requirements
- Ensures that data integrity and accuracy is maintained throughout the proofreading / amendment stages
- Biweekly project review meetings to identify any inputs that are at risk. Conducting CAPA at regular intervals for continual improvement.
- Brand meeting with Global team for innovative products.
- Monthly Reports on scheduled and fore-casted projects with Global managers.
- Appraising Guidelines and Brand standards every quarter.

# **ASSERTION**

With all my knowledge & experience looking forward towards a company which navigates excellence in packaging and personnel growth. Also to play a key role with your organization in scope of one goal.

Here by with sincere! Dinesh. D